潜  龙  轰  天  Ⅱ  暴  走  潜  龙
Tom, glad to see you made it.
汤姆  高兴你能到来
I wouldn't miss it.
我才不会错过
National Weather Institute, this is NASA Command.
国家气候学会  太空总署指挥
Transferring control of satellite Gulf-001...
转移牧场一号人造卫星控制
... in six...
六秒后
... five... four...
五  四
Do source code.
输入来源密码
禁止使用  需用核准密码
Enter current access code. Captains Trilling, Gilder...
输入现时使用密码
转移完成
We got it. It's ours.
控制了  是我们的了
Be advised...
请注意
...we have received satellite Gulf-001. Thank you, Houston.
接收到牧场一号卫星  谢谢
All right, let's see what she can do.
好了  且看它们有何本领
Activating observation function.
启动观察功能
Setting for Stage 2.
准备第二阶段
What have we got here?
这是什么？
Clean it up.
删除掉
Oh, my God, she's turning over!
她转身了
Apply full-image enhancing.
增大整幅图像
Holy guacamole!
好傢伙
The damn thing works.
这东西有效
That goddamn Travis Dane.
那该死的邓查维
If the optical circuits are this good, the targeting system must be great.
视像这么清晰目标系统定很好
Dane would love this.
丹会喜欢的
NASA thinks this is a weather satellite.
太空总暑以为这是气象卫星
Let's do a weapons check.
进行武器检查
This wasn't the bust Congress thought it was.
这不是国会认为的浪费金钱
What Congress doesn't know won't hurt them, or us.
国会不知道的事对我们没伤害
Something wrong, Captain?
有不妥吗？
It's too bad Dane wasn't here today.
可惜丹今天不在这里
Travis Dane was a nut.
屈维斯丹是个疯子
He drove his car into a lake.
他把车驶进湖里
He was crazy.
他是疯的
They find the body yet?
找到尸体没有？
No, just the car.
没有  只找到车
And a note that said: "Chance favors the prepared mind."
及写有『有志者事竟成』字条
Odd, huh?
奇怪吧？
But then, so was Dane.
丹也是怪的
Captains, you did a hell of a job.
你们做得好
Be proud of yourselves.
该引以为傲
Enjoy your weekend.
周末愉快
Thank you, General.
谢谢  将军
Can I talk to you? Excuse me.
我可和你谈吗？失陪
Have a nice weekend.
周末愉快
Go home.
回家去
There's an air show at the Air Force Academy this weekend.
周末空军学院有航空展
Maybe you'd like to join me for a drink?
要和我去吗？
Check out the new technologies.
研究新的技技
All the top brass will be there. Who knows...
高层军官会出席  很难说
...it might help your career.
会对你的事业有助
Sorry, I have plans.
抱歉  我有节目
Yeah, sure, I understand.
好的  我明白
Like the General said...
一如将军所说
...you did a good job.
你做得好
Thank you...
过奖
...sir.
长官
Let's go, you're running late.
快点  你迟到了
Where have you been?
你去了哪儿？
On a special op?
有特别任务？
Lieutenant, always a pleasure.
很荣幸
I know, you can't tell me.
我知道  你不能对我说
Sorry to hear about your brother.
很抱歉关于你哥哥的事
Me, too.
我也很难过
We must hurry to make that train. It leaves in 45 minutes.
得赶上火车  它45分钟后开行
Why are you two taking a train to California?
你们为何坐火车到加州
Would you fly if your parents died in a plane crash?
她的父母因飞机失事去世
Hi, Casey.
凯西
This place runs better when you're here. I can run it, but...
这儿比你主持时好多了  我能搞定  可是
You can't cook.
你不懂烹饪
The patrons come here for you, Casey, not for me.
顾客为你而非为我才来光顾
She's a cute kid.
可爱的孩子
- Is that your niece? - Yes. She's the only family I have left.
这是你的侄女？  是的  是我唯一亲人
I don't know if I'll recognize her.
我不知是否认得她
Come on, we'll miss that train.
快点  否则错过了火车
I missed my brother's funeral, so...
我错过兄长的葬礼  所以
...we won't miss the train.
我们不会错过火车
Your attention, please.
请注意
The Grand Continental Service from Denver to Los Angeles, now boarding.
由丹佛往麻省列车现在登车
Has a Sarah Ryback picked up any tickets?
莎拉雷贝克有拿车票吗？
Uncle Casey.
凯西叔叔
Nice to see you, too.
很高兴看见你
You've gotten big.
你亭亭玉立了
A lot can happen in five years.
五年的变化会很大
Just a moment.
等一等
So, what have you been doing?
最近在忙些什么？
Taking care of airplane crashes, funerals, stuff like that.
处理飞机失事  葬礼等事
Yeah, so...
是的  那么
Here you are. Track 3.
行了  三号月台
You know, I was thinking...
我刚才在想
I remembered that you collect teddy bears and I got you one.
你以前收集玩具熊我给你买了
It isn't as good as some of yours...
它不及你部份的藏品
...and I know you may be too mature...
你亦可能太成熟
...to hang out with teddy bears now.
不会再玩玩具熊了
It's the thought that counts.
但主要的是心意
Thanks.
谢谢
I guess I'm not trained for this.
这方面我倒没有受训
Excuse me.
请问
Can I carry your bags? Oh, nice...
我可替你拿行李吗？不错的
...medal you got there.
奖章
It's a Navy Cross.
是海军十字动章
My uncle was in the Navy, but he didn't look like you.
我叔叔是海军但他没你帅
- What is that? - This?
这是什么？
It's Mace.
喷雾防身器
All right. Listen, I have to look busy, so why don't you let me take your bag?
我要假装忙着让我替你拿行李吧
If I don't, I could get fired.
否则我会给辞退
If I get fired, I won't have enough money for college, and I'll be poor.
这样我便没钱念大学  我会穷
This will work. I like this.
这样可以了  我喜欢
What compartment did you say you were in?
你说你在哪一个车厢？
My compartment.
我的车厢
Captain Gilder...
吉尔上尉
...fancy meeting you here.
很高兴看见你
Have some champagne, Captain Trilling.
顺林上尉  喝香槟吧
Good things come to those who wait.
等候的人会有好东西
Okay, you waited.
你已等得够久了
I was wondering what that girl over there is drinking.
不知那边的女孩子喝些什么
The little girl with the tonic and lime and the bad ID?
那个喝莱姆汽水的女孩吗？
That's the one.
正是那一个
- You're not drinking? - No.
你不喝酒？
Join me. I don't like drinking alone.
和我一起喝  我不喜欢独个儿喝
There's no alcohol in that.
你的饮料没有酒
Yeah, you always knew everything, anyway.
反正你什么也知道
Do you think we could have a pleasant conversation?
我们可以聊点轻松点的吗？
Sure.
可以
Let's talk about why you and my dad stopped talking.
谈谈你和我爸为何不讲话吧
Listen...
听着
...I know that your father and I had our differences...
我知道你父亲和我意见不合
...but that doesn't mean I didn't love him.
但我爱他
But you didn't even talk.
你没不和他说话
Time goes by...
那是很久以前
...it seems to fly, and before you know it...
时光飞逝  不知不觉间
...things happen.
事情发生了
But I never thought...
但我从没想过
...I'd never get a chance to straighten things out with him.
我会没机会把事情说清楚
You know...
你知道
...he didn't get the medals in the service by being a choirboy.
他在并不是好惹的人
I don't want you talking about my father that way.
别这样子说我爸爸
I need a drink.
我要喝酒
What's the strongest stuff you got?
有什么是最烈的？
How about Puerto Rican Rum?
波多黎各甜酒如何？
Uncle Casey...
凯西叔叔
I don't want to fight.
我不想争吵
I just promised myself before I got here, that I would tell you how I felt.
我到这儿前答应自己要把感受说
Now...
现在
...let's just be friends.
我们做朋友吧
Okay.
好的
I'm going for a walk.
我到处走走
- What's up? - What's in there?
里面是什么？
It's top secret. I can't let you get in there.
是高度机密  我不能让你进去
What's in there?
里面是些什么？
Don't make me restrain you, because I've been working out, see?
别迫我出手制止你  我有练举重
It'd be easy to do that.
我轻易制服你
Okay. Restrain me.
好的  制服我吧
You want me to?
你要我这样？
Yeah.
是的
All right, if you say so. It'll be real easy.
好吧  这很容易
There's a mop...
里面有拖把
...a broom and a lot of smelly stuff you want to avoid.
扫扫以及许多发臭的东西
Who taught you that?
谁教你的？
When I was 11 years old, my uncle taught me all this neat stuff.
我十一岁时叔叔教我自卫技
That's the dude that's with you?
和你一起的那个人？
Yeah...
是的
...I guess.
我猜是的
I can do that.
我亦可以
What are you writing?
你在写什么？
It's a book. My memoirs, stuff like that.
是本书  我的回忆录
Aren't you too young to be writing your memoirs?
你这么年轻便写回忆录？
I know it's against the rules, but give me a shot of something.
我知不合规矩但给我喝杯酒吧
Can you put those up there?
你可否把它们放上去？
Yeah.
可以
What's up with that niece of yours, Miss Bruce Lee?
你的李小龙侄女怎么回事了？
She almost killed me.
她差点杀了我
Up!
上!
You taught her all that shit?
是你教她的？
I taught her a few things.
只教了她一点点
She's lucky she's a girl.
还好她是女孩子
I know some of that stuff myself.
我也懂功夫的
That's what I hear.
我听说了
Usually from you, but that's what I hear.
是我听你说的
Don't give him the brandy. I need it for the cake.
别给他白兰地  我要用来做蛋糕
Look at that.
看看
Because the train is rocking, it's cramping my style.
因为火车摇动我的手法欠流畅
I'm making this for Sarah because it's her favorite thing.
我做给莎拉吃的  她最爱吃的
Fifteen minutes, on high.
高温烘十五分钟
The rest is up to God.
其余的听天由命
Now, go find Sarah, and we'll surprise her.
去找莎拉吧  给她一个惊喜
What was that?
是什么声音？
It's called a...
那称为
...orgasm.
高潮
Sounds like torpedoes. We must be in dark territory.
似是雷管  列车一定是在无讯号
What the hell is this?
是什么回事？
They're not our guys.
他们不是铁路局的人
What's the trouble?
有什么事？
What's going on?
是什么回事？
Someone's been shot.
有人中枪
Where?
在哪儿？
Here.
就在这儿
Loco secured.
火车受控了
Move! You have four minutes.
快!你们有四分钟
Everybody to the back of the train! Don't make me ask twice!
大家到火车后面去  别要我再说
Everybody up those stairs! Move it! Come on!
各人上去!快点!
Shut that bitch up or I will! Let's move it!
要那婊子住口否则杀了她
Get up the stairs!
上楼梯!
What the fuck is this? Anything else? Go! Get out of here!
这是什么？还有什么？走吧!
Open the door to the baggage car!
打开行李舱门!
Check the baggage.
搜查行李
Baggage checked.
搜过了
Any other heroes?
还有英雄吗？
Trouble in the dining car. One casualty.
餐车有一人死了
Take cover!
找掩护!
Four cooks. Check.
四名厨师  查过了
Copy that. Continue with the cleanup.
知道  继续驱赶乘客
We leave in 20 seconds.
二十秒后离去
This, I'm trained for.
这方面我训练有素
Oh, my God.
天啊
Well, here you are.
你们在这儿
The last place anyone would expect to find you.
料不到在这儿找到你们
Amazing.
不可思议
Put something on.
穿衣服
Have a seat, Captains.
请坐  上尉们
They said you were dead.
他们说你死了
Yeah, very restful.
是的  很安详
No phone calls.
没有电话
You two have been very naughty.
你们可真顽皮
ATAC has strict rules against employees getting involved with each other.
单位命令禁止雇员发生关系
Is that what this is about?
你是为此而来的吗？
Yeah, right. I faked my own death and hijacked a passenger train...
是的  我装死以方便去劫载客火
...because I care about who you're fucking.
因为我关心你和谁上床
No, I wondered what other rules you'd be willing to break.
不  我想知你会违反那一条规例
On-line transmission's ready, sir.
准备传送
Don't go away.
别走开
Good evening, everyone. This is your captor speaking.
各位晚安  我是你们的挪掠者
There's been a slight change in your travel plans tonight.
你们今晚的行程有些许改变
You have, you will note, been moved to the last two cars of the train...
请你们移到火车最后两节车厢
... for your own well-being.
是为了你们的安全
First, I'd like to call your attention to the highly trained men...
首先请注意受高度训练的人员
... with the automatic weapons in your cars.
他们手持自动武器
In the event of an emergency, they may be called upon to shoot you.
在紧急情况下他们会奉命杀你们
Your safety is our primary concern.
我们关心你们的安全
However, if you try anything stupid...
可是  若你们轻举妄动
... federal regulations require that I kill you.
依据联邦法我会杀了你们
He's insane.
他疯了
So, please...
所以求求你们
... no hero shit.
别程英雄
Your access code, please.
给我密码
I'll never...
我永不会
...give you the code.
告诉你密码的
The psychological profile we have on you says you will.
你的心说你会的
However, if you wish to prove the profile incorrect...
若想证明档案是错的
...sit back and see what happens when an intensely hot needle...
那就别动看看当那炙热的铁针
...penetrates the lens of one of the most beautiful eyes on earth.
刺进这明目时会变得怎样
The needle point will pass through the lens with very little difficulty.
铁针可轻易刺过水晶体
The heat will cauterize and seal the wound.
热力会烧灼及封合伤口
But the instrument will continue to transfer heat...
但铁针仍继续把热力
...to the fluid in the eyeball.
传至眼内的液体
The fluid comes to a boil and...
液体沸腾而
...the eyeball itself...
眼球
...explodes.
爆炸
J-B-N-1...
J  B  N
1 2 1
1  2  1
He can't use it.
他无法使用的
Why do you think he's doing this?
你认为他何以这样做？
Because he's crazy.
因为他是疯的
You can argue that point later. Next!
你们可稍后再争论  下一个!
Are we up for this?
我们准备好没有？
You can't hack into the system. There are quadruple blocks.
你无法进入系统  它有四重防御
Even if he could, the codes need to be entered simultaneously.
即使可进入各密码亦要同时输入
There's not enough power here. You've seen the ATAC generators.
这儿能量不够你见过单位发电机
Oh, for Christ's sake, it's impossible!
这是不可能的!
You know that!
你是知道的
The codes are different! You can't use them anymore!
密码是不同的!你不能再用它们
It's no good! He can't use them!
没用的!他无法使用!
For God's sake, please, give him the code! Give him the code!
快告诉他密码!给他密码!
E-U-I...
E  U  I
...4- 7-6.
4  7  6
I not only invented Grazer, I've updated it...
我不单发明了牧场一号还把它增
...to use part of the electromagnetic spectrum ATAC is only dimly aware of.
使用单位所不知的电子磁场光普
What is that?
那是什么？
As long as we're moving, the signal is completely transparent.
只要我们在动讯号是完全透明的
As you can see...
你亦知道
...we're on a choo-choo. No stop signs for six hours.
我们在火车上六小时内不会停车
ATAC would kill to get a hold of this technology.
单位会很想掌握这种技技
In fact...
事实上
...I'm sure they'll try.
我相信他们想得到
Works just as well underground, underwater.
这技技在地底  水底均发挥
I not only designed the system...
我不单设计系统
...I designed the blocks.
亦设计了防御
执行超驰
What're you doing, Dane?
你做什么？
I'm hacking into ATAC, Linda.
我在连接单位系统
Now...
现在
...watch...
看着
...this.
这个
禁止使用  输入使用密码
转移完成
It's mine again.
再由我掌握了
Shut the fuck up!
住口!
We're locked.
我们瞄准了
Oh, they're still here.
他们还没走
I don't need them anymore. They can go now.
我不再需要他们  他们可以走
Move it, asshole!
快点
Come on, gorgeous.
来吧
Don't you know that man's crazy? Do you realize what he could do?
难道你不知那人是疯的？
He's paying me a lot of money.
他付给我许多钱
That's why you're doing this?
原来如此
Goddamn it.
可恶
Three-hundred thousand pages of code...
三十万页密码  或是
...or 60 minutes of triple-X interactive...
60分钟的色情互动
...rubber-and-leather-bondage porno.
性变态虐待淫衣物
Technology can be used for beauty...
技技可用以美化
...or debasement.
或是降格
And until you plug it in...
直至你接驳上
...you just can't tell.
是难以知道的
遥控使用能力
天啊
I seem to have brought the targeting codes.
我带了目标瞄准密码
I want every window and door locked and secured. Airtight.
我要稳当关上毎一扇门及窗
The train is secure.
火车受控制
The major installation is T minus ten. The phone lines are two.
十分钟完成主要安装电话两分钟
We're sweeping the train for stragglers. Excuse me.
我们搜查火车找游勇
Okay, people...
好了  各位
...let's start this party.
开始派对吧
轨迹转移
关闭牧场一号卫星
What's going on?
什么回事？
Captain, give me a report.
上尉  给我报告
I'm still searching.
我仍在追查
Try this.
试这个
- What is it? - It's gone, sir.
这是什么？  它消失了  先生
- What's gone? - Grazer One.
什么消失了？  牧场一号卫星
What do you mean, it's gone? Bring it up on the screen.
什么意思？它还显示在屏幕上
It's like someone took it.
好像有人拿走了
How could someone take it?
怎可能有人拿走？
Nobody knows it's there.
没人知道它在上空
- Find the damn thing. - We designed it to be undetectable.
找它的下落  它设计成没法追测的
But not from us, for Christ's sake!
但我们可以
I want a full systems-check in two minutes.
我要全面检查系统  两分钟后要
We're in Code 2 status.
已进入二号密码
Gilder, Trilling and Tom Breaker, ASAP.
立即找吉儿  顺林和贝克来
All right, let's move it!
快一点
Mr. Penn, ATAC is now locked out of their own system.
彭先生  他们无法进入系统
Grazer One is fully under my control.
牧场一号卫星全由我控制
I thought you were one of those ugly men with guns.
我以为你是持枪的那班人
What are you doing?
你做什么？
It was just a nice day for a stroll. What's in here?
天气适宜到外面走走  这是什么
It's the baggage car, but don't go in. They shot at me in there.
行李室  别进去  他们向我开枪
What are you doing?
你做什么？
Trying to get killed?
想送命吗？
There are guys with guns out there.
他们有枪
Come here.
过来
- I ain't coming out there. - Don't make me yell. Come here.
我不会过来  别要我大叫  过来
Investors on the line?
接通了投资者？
Clients from Asia and the Middle East are standing by, sir.
来自亚洲及中东的客户
Gentlemen.
各位？
How are we today? How's the weather out there? Sunny and sandy?
今天好吗？天气如何？
Now, look, it's demonstration time.
现在是示范时间
Some of you have trouble with the idea of...
你们有人不相信
...a non-terrestrially originated seismic event.
非原发性地区的地震活动
But I want you to watch China very closely for the next ten minutes.
但我想你们紧密注意中国
- What's the problem? - The system won't let us in.
有什么问题  系统不让我们使用
The system? What do you mean? We are the system.
什么意思？我们就是系统
- Any word from Gilder and Trilling? - We're still looking.
吉儿和顺林有消息吗？  仍在找他们
You lose them, too?
亦不见了他们？
This is where the shit will really start to fly. A fertilizer plant in Guangzhou.
广州肥料场会粪便四践
A fertilizer plant?
肥料场？
Yeah, I'm going to shock the world by spreading ca-ca all over the place.
我把粪便弄的四处皆是震惊世界
Guangzhou is a chemical weapons plant posing as a fertilizer plant.
广州的肥料场其实是化武工场
We know this. The Chinese know we know.
我们知道  中国亦知我们知道
But we pretend we don't, and the Chinese pretend they believe we don't know...
我们假装不知中国假装我们不知
...but they know.
但他们知道
Everybody knows.
人人均知道
I'm gonna pull the brake cord, stop the train and get the hell out of here.
我去把火车刹停  逃之大吉
I'm going to die. I'm a fucking porter.
我会死的  我是侍者
You're a fucking cook.
你是个厨师
You gotta trust me on this one, okay?
你在这件事上要相信我
Is there a phone or com unit here?
这儿有电话或通讯器吗？
There's a radio in the locomotive and a pay phone downstairs in the lounge.
火车有无线电楼下酒廊有电话
I'll try to call the cavalry.
我会设法通知当局
Meanwhile, search the bags for a weapon or something that can be used as one.
你搜查行李是否有武器
If I even touch a bag, I lose my job.
我碰行李便会给辞退
I'm more concerned...
我更关心
...about the lives of these people being held as hostages.
给胁持作人质的乘客生命
The hostages.
人质
I don't want them hurt.
我不想他们受伤害
Now, pay close attention, Mr. Penn.
请你留心  彭先生
I'm about to make the Bhopal disaster look like a Girl Scout picnic.
我会把大灾难弄成似是小事一桩
There. It's back.
在那儿  回来了
You see, it's nothing. A minor glitch. False alarm.
没什么的  是轻微出错  虚惊一场
What the hell is that?
那是什么东西？
Poison gas, chemical fire...
毒气  化学火灾
...total devastation for a 100-mile radius.
方圆一百里内完全毁灭
Thousands of people are going to die.
以千计的人会死去
Just listen and do what I say.
你听着和依我吩咐做
Cover and concealment...
掩护和隐藏
...you know as much as anybody!
你跟别人同样知道
Right.
脱下白色的外衣  是的
You touch me again, it's your ass.
你再碰我便会有麻烦
Targeting codes.
目标密码
- They've started our targeting sequence. - It's arming.
他们开始我们的次序
This is nuts. There must be some kind of malfunction.
太荒妙  定是操作错误
It's being controlled elsewhere.
它在别处受到控制
Oh, Jesus, the target's mainland China.
目标是中国
Not China!
不会吧!
Not somebody nuclear.
不能瞄准核子国家
What's going on?
是什么回事？
Sweet Jesus!
天啊
She's into acquisition mode.
它进入进取模式
Somebody shut it down!
把它关掉吧!
They fired me.
他们辞退我
Took everything.
夺去一切
She's powering up for a hit.
它准备命中东西
Said the technology wasn't essential.
说这技技不需要
Blow it!
炸了它!
Shut it down!
关掉它!
No response.
没反应
They wanted it! They'll get it!
他们要的  定会得到
执行
有志者事竟成
That's what Dane used to say.
彭以前这样说
Call Admiral Bates at the Pentagon.
通知五角大厦的贝兹上将
Admiral Bates is here in Colorado attending an air show.
他在科罗拉多出席航空展
Then get him here, now.
那立即要他前来
Gentlemen, as you can see, it works.
各位  你们看见它是有效的
This is a one-time offer.
这是只此一次的机会
Two hundred feet below the Pentagon, is an itty-bitty crack...
五角大厦二百尺下的小裂缝
...which I propose to make great, big and wide.
我提议把它加大加阔
Directly above it is a strike-hard nuclear reactor.
在它上面的是核子反应器
It ain't hard enough.
但它承受不了攻击
We'll take out the Pentagon...
我们消灭五角大厦
...and God...
神
...Allah...
真主
...and the wind's willing...
若风向对的话
...Washington and most of the Eastern Seaboard as well.
会遍及华府及东岸大部份地区
The fee:
费用:
One billion dollars.
十亿元
A billion dollars.
十亿元？
I owe people money.
我欠别人钱
Oh, shit.
糟了
What is this place?
这是什么地方？
Here we go.
我们要有准备
- I don't know, nor does Congress. - Who's paying for it?
我不知道  国会亦不知
What the hell is going on?
是什么回事？
Don't say this is just a weather station.
别说它是个气象站
Bring the rendering up.
显示在屏幕上
Recently we deployed a particle-beam weapon into orbit.
我们把分子光束武器送上轨迹
In English, please.
说简单一点
It's a major cash cow. Particle-beam technology, it's the earthquake deal.
需要许多钱  分子光束技技
It's my understanding we shut that program down.
以我所知已终止了那计划
We financed it.
我们加以资助
Breaker, what?
贝克
This goddamn thing works now?
这东西发挥效用了？
It works so effectively...
它效能极好
...that if we targeted the Los Angeles fault lines, in 15 seconds...
若瞄准罗省地震断层  十五秒后
...Arizona would be beachfront property.
亚历桑那会变成滨海地区
The problem is, someone else is commanding the satellite.
问题是  别人指挥了卫星
We couldn't find it or destroy it...
我们无法找到或摧毁它
...so we were unable to stop it.
所以我们不可以阻止它
Oh, my God!
天啊!
China's earthquake?
中国的地震？
We have full deniability.
我们可完全否认
Shit!
糟透!
That's typical.
那是典型作风
Typical Agency bullshit! Do you know who we're dealing with?
中情局作风  你知对手是谁吗？
We think it's Travis Dane, the guy who designed the system.
是设计这系统的邓查维
- One of our people? - Not anymore.
我们的人？
He was decommissioned. Last month he was an apparent suicide.
他给辞退了  上月他自杀身亡
He's brilliant. He can do anything he puts his mind to, but he's crazy.
他很聪明  能干  但神经病
Why would you hire a maniac?
你为何雇用狂徒？
Because...
因为
...sane people do not build weapons like this.
正常的人无法造出这样的武器
You'd think we'd learn from that.
你认为我们可从中学习
All right, we're upgrading to Code 3.
好吧  把紧急状态提升
Gentlemen, let's find the satellite, and the bastard, now!
我们快找出那卫星及那杂种吧
No power.
没有能量
Cover and conceal. You know about that, right?
掩护和隐藏  你懂得的吧？
You know about that, right?
你懂得这样做吧？
One of our customers has a small personal favor to ask.
我们有一客户有私事想求助
He wants you to blow up an airplane.
他想你炸毁一客机
Tell him to forget about it. I'm going to blow up the Pentagon.
告诉他不行  我会炸五角大厦
He either gets on board or gets left behind.
他不加入便无法参与
But, sir, the gentleman's ex-wife is on board of this jet.
但这人的前妻在这机上
请转告贝兹上将:
He wants you to blow up a jet going 500 miles an hour...
他想你用为地下攻击设计的武器
...with a weapon designed for subterranean strikes?
炸毁时速五百里的飞机？
He says he'll pay us an additional $100 million.
他说会额外给我们一亿元
Really?
真的？
Do we have it's transponder numbers?
异频收发器的号码？
Sending them now.
他现时送来
I can do this.
我可办到
His ex-wife is history once the money is in our account.
钱存进我们的帐户他前妻便没命
Grazer One will be in position in...
一号会移至位置
He has five minutes to make the deposit.
他有五分钟
里高餐室
线路繁忙
The money's hitting Zurich...
钱已存入苏黎士
...now!
对!
Good. Here we go.
好  开始
Grazer's back on-line.
牧场一号又回到银幕
- lf they hooked up, we're in trouble. - Pegasus C Team is in range.
若他们联上我们便有麻烦
We have a B-2 bomber with two anti-satellite missiles on board.
B2轰炸机上有反卫星导弹
I thought you cut the power downstairs.
我以为你已截断下面的电源
30秒后重发
Pegasus locked on Grazer One. On your command.
战机导弹瞄准卫星听候你的命令
Fire.
发射
Can we get it before it fires?
我们可成功吗？
They are so slow.
他们很慢
- Why is it counting? - Still getting the feed.
为何仍在数？  资料仍在传送
Earthquake in midair.
空中地震
That is the goddamnedest thing I've ever seen.
我从没见过这么精彩的
What the hell did we shoot down?
我们击落了什么？
21秒后重发
I'll ask you again, if we didn't shoot down Grazer One, what did we shoot?
若没有击落卫星我们击落什么？
Check on Herb downstairs.
到下面去看看赫拔
Train noise eliminated from the transmission.
已在传送中删去火车车声
Let's get ready to call home.
我们准备致电老家吧
What's up?
怎么了？
- Where'd you get the gun? - Get anything?
你哪里弄到枪的？
I got a fishing rod, pool cue and clothes.
鱼杠  桌球棒  衣服
You're a useless bastard.
你是没用的浑蛋
Encrypted, no good. This is a.45, okay?
这是点四五的枪
Dynamic tension, left hand, right hand, palms pressed together, okay?
左手  右手  掌心紧压一起
Cover your ass, 12, 3, 6, 9, wherever you look always.
经常要攒前顾后  左看右望
Never look in a direction where the gun ain't pointing, understand?
枪指向那里便望那里  明白吗？
Who the hell is that?
那是谁？
Jesus Christ!
主耶稣
Not quite, General Cooper, although I have sort of risen from the dead.
我不是  虽然我从死里复活
No, it's just your old friend, Travis Dane.
我只是你的老朋友屈维斯  丹
You remember? The guy you fired!
你记得吗？给你辞退的人
And I bet now you're probably asking yourselves:
我相信你现时在问自己:
"What the hell did we just shoot down?"
我们击落了什么？
The answer is:
答案是:
The NSA's best and only functional real-time down-looking satellite...
国家安全机构唯一有效的卫星
... the NSP-1.
NSP一号
You'll probably be calling them any minute now, asking them for its use.
你可能查问他们有关卫星的用途
Unfortunately, since even they don't know where it is...
可惜  由于他们不知它的下落
... they can't help you.
亦无法帮你们
Have you got him?
查到他的下落吗？
I'm closing in.
快可以了
You do know where the last transmission came from.
你是知道上次在何处传送
You're probably closing in fast...
你就可能查到
... on Grazer One's probable location.
牧场一号的可能位置
It's in there somewhere...
它就在某一处
... hiding among those 50 ghost satellites I've created...
躲在我所创造的50枚假卫星中
... just for you.
为你而造的
Motherfucker's gone.
那捞种死了
As my demonstration just proved...
我的示范证明了
... Grazer One is viable...
游牧者一号是可行的
... and can produce results.
亦能产生效果
Reproducible results.
可再生的效果
And to prove it...
而为了证明
... I'm going to give you another demonstration of my masterpiece.
我会给你们再示范一次
In 45 minutes...
45分钟后
... as soon as Grazer One is in position for a clear shot...
牧场一号到了发射的位置时
... I'm going to hit the Pentagon with a 98 percent blast.
我会用九成八的威力炸五角大厦
Enough to fracture the nuclear reactor you claim you don't have under there.
可摧毁你们说并不存在的反应器
You son of a bitch.
你这王八蛋
We'll have fallout.
会有辐射性微尘
We'll have devastation.
会有毁灭
I've got things to do.
我有事情要办
I want you to remember:
我要你们记着:
I was smarter than all of you before I worked there.
我在上班前已比你们聪明
I was smarter than all of you while I worked there.
受雇工作时亦比你们聪明
And I'm still smarter than all of you.
我仍比你们聪明
Au revoir.
再见
He sure didn't go this way. We would've heard him.
他不是从这儿走否则我们会听到
What are the odds of tracking Grazer down in time?
及时追查牧场一号下落的机会如
We should check over Paris.
我们该查询巴黎
Considering the area we must cover...
试想我们要函盖的范围
That's why it's called "space."
因此它称为太空
What's that, son? Speak up.
什么？  大声一点
Well...
这个
...I was just saying...
我只是说
...that's why they call it "space," because...
因此它给称为  太空  因为
...there's a lot of it.
有许多的空间
Thank you.
谢谢
Just be quiet, please.
但请静一点
Where are you going?
你去哪儿？
Front of the train.
到火车前面
To look for the radio.
找无线电
Stay out of sight and don't get killed.
你别现身也别送命
Safety off...
扳开安全制
...dynamic tension...
动力
...aim... shoot.
瞄准  发射
That's their ass now.
他们没命了
Do you know what this is? This is a Navy Cross.
你知这是什么吗？海军十字动章
It's awarded for bravery.
是英勇作战获勋的
This is my father's. Uncle Casey's got two of them.
这是我爸的  凯西叔叔有两枚
He's got medals that are so secret...
他拿的奖章是那么的秘密
...he can never show them to anybody.
他从不给别人看的
He won't let anything happen to us.
他不会让我们有事的
I guess he's a hero.
我猜他是个英雄
这火车不能操作
We have an intruder.
有入侵者
Sweep the train.
搜查火车
搜查
Found our intruder?
找到入侵者吗？
Negative. We're still looking.
找不到  仍在找
You clear?
你找过？
We're checking.
在找
Nothing.
没发现
We're clear here.
没有入侵者
Have you checked everywhere?
你到处搜查过
Check on the roof.
在车顶搜查
What?
什么事？
On top!
他在车顶!  在车顶!
We're under fire!
我们受到攻击!
Go get him.
去捉他
Got him. He fell off of one of the first cars.
是大个子  他从前列车卡掉下
She said he fell over here.
她说他在这儿掉下
There's blood here. Here!
这儿有血迹
She got him. He fell between the first car and the locomotive.
她杀了他  他从两卡车中间掉下
Is this a confirmation?
这确定了吗？
He's now hamburger. He's probably spread about halfway across the state.
他已给展成肉酱  陈尸路轨了
We got him.
杀了他
But the bastard took out six men.
但他干掉我们六个人
You stay here, okay? I'm going back.
你留在这儿  我回去
Be careful.
小心
You said these men were good.
你说他们训练有素
Who was he?
他是谁？
What was he doing downstairs?
他在下面做什么？
The man is a soldier-of-fortune freak.
那人是个雇拥兵狂徒
Ran a war camp in Alabama. They sat around playing paint ball.
主办作战营  学员作模拟战争
That's not the whole story.
事情不是这么简单
The relationship between Penn and Dane resurfaced during Desert Storm.
沙莫风暴暴露了丹和彭的关系
When Dane apparently died, we pulled surveillance off them.
丹死后  我们撤销对他们的监视
We're aware of that.
这个我们知道
The connection is tenuous.
两人关系是模糊的
Let me tell you what it really is.
我告诉你他们有什么关系
It's another classic example of the CIA not doing their homework.
另一个中情局没清楚调查的例子
Excuse me?
什么？
In the last few years, Penn developed a network of contacts.
过去数年彭发展出一联繁网
North Korea, here in the US, in particular in the Middle East.
北韩  美国  尤其在中东
Best guess is this: If he's hooked up with Dane, they have the money to do it.
若他和丹结合  他们有资金可用
Why did he need power?
他为何要电源？
The phone!
用电话
传送成功
Call Philippe, tell him he's working tomorrow.
通知菲力  告诉他明天上班
Damn it!
可恶!
On second thought, he worked yesterday. Call Antoine.
他昨天已上班  找安东尼吧
No, there's no bullet. No bullet in here.
不  我体内没子弹  你中枪？
You think this is "been shot"?
你以为中枪是这样的吗？
This ain't it.
才不是呢
Let's see here...
让我看看
Access encoded...
不能使用
Gigabyte of RAM should do the trick.
随取记忆体的十亿位元组该可以
We are in. What have we got?
找到什么？
"Phone book...
电话薄
"...recipes.
食谱
"Chicken cannelloni...
鸡肉卷
"...fruit salad with crystallized ginger."
水果沙拉和蜜饯生姜
Sounds good.
很不错
Where are we?
我们在哪里
We're about right there.
大约在这里
There, about 200 miles, is where we come out of the mountain.
我们从那儿离开大山约二百里
We're without phones for four hours?
没电话可用达四小时
"Ryback's Tactics."
雷贝克兵法
Casey-fucking-Ryback?
雷贝克？
Jesus Christ.
天啊
Who's Casey-fucking-Ryback?
雷贝克是谁？
Casey Ryback's a former SEAL Team Captain, a counter-terrorist expert.
是反恐怖份子专家
He was my instructor.
他是我的教官
He's the best.
是最好的
I thought you were.
我以为你是最好的
Did you see the body she shot?
你看见她枪杀的尸体吗？
No, just a lot of blood. If you get run over by a train...
没有  只看见许多血  给火车碾压
Did you see the body?
你看见尸体吗？
I assumed he was dead.
我假设他死了
Assumption is the mother of fuckups.
假设是败事之母
I want every man to resume a full train search...
各人继续搜索火车
...inside and out, car by car.
逐车卡的搜
Including all AC ducting, all paneling, the roof, undercarriage.
包括空调管剿  间隔车顶  车盘
Absolutely everything! Right now!
不可遗漏!快去!
I can do this.
我可以的
You think he's alive?
你看他还活着
Until I have confirmation otherwise.
除非我证实他死了
What is he doing on my train besides killing your men?
他除杀掉你的人还在车上做什么
Check the manifest. See if he's traveling with anyone.
检查乘客名单看是否有人和他同行
You said your million-dollar mercenaries would be more than enough.
你说你的百万雇佣兵已足够了
They are. Print that.
他们是的  打印出来
Move it!
快走!
You picked the wrong place to hang out with your legs spread.
你找错地方张开双腿呆站着
No, I'm hanging on right here.
我可支持下去的
Plus one.
雷贝克和一人
Could be a girlfriend or child.
可能是女友或孩子
Could be his wife.
可能是他妻子
A man doesn't call his wife "plus one."
妻子是不会说成是  和一人  的
So what? You looking for some babe?
你要找妞儿吗？
Some bait.
是个饵
What the hell?
这是什么？
This isn't a produce list, this is...
这不是货单  这是
Oh, my God.
天啊
Who's fucking blood is this?
这是谁的血？
Go back to the lounge car. Check the bar downstairs.
回到酒吧车卡  搜查下面的酒吧
What are you doing now?
怎办？
What am I doing? I'm making a bomb.
我在制炸弹
容缩椰子油
What's he looking for?
他找什么？
Me.
找我
Your lunch?
你的午餐？
When do I get some action?
我何时显身手？
We're going to take a bargaining chip to protect the hostages.
我们要拿保护人质的筹码
I want an evac order for the President, and senior staff members...
我要下令疏散总统和高级幕僚
...on an Alpha status now, and try not to cause a panic.
首要任务  并设法别引起恐慌
I don't think we have a chance in hell.
我看我们没有机会
Hi, honey. It's me.
亲爱的  是我
I want you to take Jamie, and I want you to get out of Washington tonight.
我要你带同吉米今晚离开华府
Go to your mother's.
到你母亲家中
Yeah, and...
是的  还有
...honey...
亲爱的
...don't tell anyone.
别对别人说
What's your name?
你叫什么？
Zachs. Bobby Zachs.
柴企  巴比柴企
You're not on the list.
你不在名单内
I'm an employee.
我是职员
Where's your uniform?
你的制服呢？
I'm deadheading, getting a free ride.
我免费乘车
Navy Cross.
海军十字动章
Mace.
喷雾防身器
Not Mace...
这个不是
...pepper spray.
是胡椒喷剂
Sold to civilians. Once you get used to it...
卖给平民的  一旦习惯了
...it just clears the sinuses.
可收通鼻之效
Get her and let's go.
把她带走
Let her go.
放了她
Why do you need lighter fluid?
你为何要打火机液体？
It's like a detonator.
这有如是雷管
Okay, Bobby, get in the elevator.
好了  包比  进升降机去
I must go beep someone.
我要传呼别人
Imagine a fire from New York to Charleston.
试想像由纽约查斯顿的大火
We can do this.
我们可以成功的
你失败了
Get a man on the roof!
找人上车顶!
I need two more downstairs in the next two cars!
下两个车卡派两人到下面去
The bastard is using the AC ducting!
那混蛋利用空调剿管
Computer's down!
电脑失灵
You and you, get to the baggage car!
快去行李卡
Get him!
抓他!
I got the CD.
我拿到光谍了
He's downstairs. Go get him.
他在下面  找他
Go.
走
Now.
去
They have the CD!
他们拿走光谍
The targeting CD!
那目标光谍
I can't do anything without it!
没有它我做什么也不行
Let's go!
走吧
Don't shoot the intruder.
别杀死他
He has the CD.
他有光谍
Hold it right there!
别走!
Hand over the CD.
把光谍给我
They're off the train.
他们掉下去
Stop the train.
停车
Back up.
退后
This train...
这火车
...might as well be 20 tons of scrap metal without that CD.
没有光谍便成20吨的废铁
Hold it!
且慢!
Come on, move!
快!
Hook up right here.
锡着
Wait here.
在这里等
Safety off...
开保险
...dynamic tension...
动力!
Ass!
没命了
It's the porter.
是那侍者
Check the porter!
找那侍者!
You cocksucker!
你这小浑球
He's got an accomplice!
他有同党
It's the porter. We're on to him.
是那侍者  我们快抓到他
Don't shoot him.
别杀他
He could also have the CD.
光谍亦可能在他身上
Don't put a bullet in it.
别向他开枪
Tell me about the porter.
把侍者的事告诉我
The CD.
光谍
Hand it over.
交出来
Down there.
在下面
Where did he go under the train?
他在火车下哪一处？
Two cars up.
前面两车卡
You pricks never learn.
你们不识相
Freeze!
别动!
Get your damn hands up.
举手!
Up where I can see them!
把手举高!
Where's the CD?
光谍在哪？
I ripped my pocket. It fell out.
口袋撕破了  它丢了
Don't bullshit with me. Show me that CD...
快拿光谍出来
...or I'll cap your black ass, bitch!
否则我杀了你
Empty your pockets.
把口袋翻出
Right now!
快点!
All right, man!
好吧
I'm just a kid. I'm just a kid, I'm trying to tell you.
我只是个年轻人  我想对你说
- Do it! - I lost it there.
我丢失了
I ripped my pocket. Everything fell out.
什么也丢了
Only thing I've got is your ass!
我可杀了你
Porter checked.
查过侍者了
"Chance favors the prepared mind."
有志者事竟成
Oh, shit.
糟了
Take us west. Full ahead.
往西走  全速开行
Oh, shit.
糟了
Your uncle wasn't as good as I thought.
你叔叔不是我所想的那么好
You're back on-line. Now, get on with it.
你已同步了  继续吧
We haven't lost anything vital. I have enough to do this.
我们没失去重要仪器  仍可继续
Houston, Tranquility Base here. We are now at T minus 20 minutes...
休斯顿  现时是二十分钟
...and...
而且
...counting.
在倒数
That bastard started the countdown.
那浑蛋开始倒数了
Williams.
威廉
Eliminate orbits that don't offer Grazer a shot at Washington in 20 minutes.
二十分钟后删除不能令卫星射向  华府的轨迹
We must eliminate all of them.
我们要删除全部
- We only have one Pegasus left. - We don't need one.
但只剩一枚导弹
On the last one we lock on the satellite and use the self-destruct.
最后一个瞄准卫星采自毁程式
Make it happen.
定要成事
Start knocking them off.
开始消灭卫星
- We've eliminated 22 possibilities. - Excellent.
我们已删去22个可能性
Twenty-three.
23个
A cook has a message.
厨师有口信给你
He says he has a Code 3 message.
他说他有三号密码口信
Patch him through on the audio.
把他转驳到扬声器
Is Joint Chief of Staff Bates there, please?
贝兹在吗？
This is Admiral Bates speaking.
我是贝兹上将
Sir, I have a fax message for you.
我有传真讯息给你
It reads:
写着:
"Admiral, a force of armed men...
上将  一伙武装人员
"...probably numbering above 20...
人数可能在20名以上
"...has taken over the Grand Continental passenger train...
已胁持了由丹佛往麻省的
"...traveling from Denver to LA.
大陆火车客车
"Key signature equipment of...
主要电磁射线仪器
"...high-bandwidth satellite transmission equipment has been loaded on board. "
卫星传送仪器已装置在车上
- It's Dane! - "Aggressors appear to be professionals...
是丹麦人!  攻击者似乎很专业
- "...and fully armed." - Get me the exact location of that train.
并且全副武装  查出那列车的正确地点
Who sent the message?
是谁发出这讯息的
Casey Ryback.
雷贝克
Casey Ryback? Casey Ryback's on this train?
雷贝克在这列车上？
What is he doing?
他做什么？
Leave it to Casey.
交给凯西好了
On vacation with his niece, sir.
和他的侄女渡假
What's the closest air-strike group?
最接近的空军攻击部队
Stealth, sir, from the air show.
飞机展览的隐形轰炸机
Get them armed and on their way.
立即命它们起飞
There's over 200 people on that train.
车上有二百多名乘客
There are over eight million people in Washington.
华盛顿有八百多万人
Unless Ryback performs a miracle in 18 minutes, I have no choice.
除非赖能在18分内有奇迹出现
Scramble the Stealths.
派隐形战机
I'm disappointed.
我很失望
I looked forward to going head-to-head with the great Casey...
我很想和凯西单打独斗
Man, that was good.
很出色
Did he teach you that?
是他教你的吗？
Pity...
可惜
...you could have been very, very good.
你会是很好的战士
She's insurance, leave her alone.
别惹她
Ryback's gone, Dane.
雷贝克死了
Did you see the body?
你看见尸体吗？
"Assumption is the mother of all fuckups."
假设是败事之母
It doesn't matter, she'll die anyway...
没关系  反正她会死
...with all the rest.
和其他乘客一起
Ryback may be dead, he may be alive...
雷贝克可能死了  可能活着
...but he is not on this train.
但他并不在列车上
I shouldn't have got back on this train.
我不该回到车上的
Drop the gun.
扔下枪
Drop it!
扔下
I never considered myself vicious...
我从不认为自己邪恶
...but you...
但你
...you're like a cockroach!
你像是蟑螂
So what do you do when the bastard shows himself?
蟑螂出现时你会怎办？
You squash him, right?
你捏死它  对吗？
You get what I'm saying here, busboy?
你明白我的意思吗？杂工？
I'm a porter...
我是侍者
...not a busboy.
不是杂工
Okay, Mr. Porter...
侍者先生
...you got balls, man.
你有种
So I'm going to let you decide.
所以我让你决定
You want to see it coming...
你想正面死去
...or to turn around?
还是背向着受死？
Say...
你
...want to help me?
要救我吗？
You're a bad motherfucker.
你真不好惹
Let's go kick some more ass, though.
但我们去杀敌吧
Cool, man.
好极
Congratulations, gentlemen...
恭喜  各位
...there is now one billion dollars...
现时有十亿元
...waiting for us in the land of banks, cheese and cuckoo clocks.
在瑞士等着我们去拿
All we must do now...
我们现在要做的
... is blow up Washington, DC.
是把华府炸了
That'd be the fire.
他说的是那场火
You will be picked up at the next stop.
下一站会有人接你们
Thank you for your participation.
多谢你们参加
It is sort of true.
我说的不算错
You're traveling in another dimension...
你们在另一空间行进
...not only of sight and sound, but of mind.
不是视与听的  而是意志的
There's a signpost up ahead. Your next stop:
前面有一路标  你们的下一站
Dark territory.
无讯号
Who says I have a one-track mind?
谁说我的想法呆扳
The town's on the wrong side.
火车在错误的一方
We're not on the right tracks.
我们入错了路轨
We always pass it on the inside, not the outside.
我们由内面驶过  不是由外面
Where are they taking us?
我们去哪里
8:00, Nevada Petrol Express.
8时内华达巡逻快车驶过
We're going to collide. If we don't do something, we'll die.
会相撞  若不想办法便会没命
This is a big motherfucker.
那列车很大
It has six locos up front, about a mile long...
前面有六卡机车  长约一里
...and has 800,000 gallons of gasoline.
载有八十万加仑汽油
You won't let them get away with it.
你不会让他们得程吧？
No, I'm going to get my bag of tricks...
不  我会施展浑身解数
...and we are going to rescue these hostages.
我们会拯救那些人质
撞车警报
That's the Nevada Petrol Express.
那是内华达快车
It's carrying 800,000 gallons of gasoline.
载有八十万加仑的汽油
Can't we contact them?
无法联络他们吗？
Not while they're in dark territory. There is no reception in the canyons.
在无讯号地区便不能
When will they hit? Will it do the job?
何时会相撞？能摧毁仪器吗？
It's going to be close, but... I don't think so.
会很接近但我看不会
We're closing in, sir, but there are 11 possibles left.
快完成了但仍剩下十一个可能性
Can you eliminate them in time?
可及时消除它们吗？
No, sir.
不行
Foxtrot Flight, vectoring in on target.
狐步战机  向目标飞去
Green light the bombers.
准许轰炸机执行任务
Roger. Foxtrot heading zero.
知道  狐步飞向目标
God forgive us.
主原谅我们
Something's coming in.
雷达有动静
Intermittent signal, very faint.
断续的讯号  很微弱
F-117s.
F一117战机
Stealths.
是隐形战机
They found us.
他们发现我们了
Casey-fucking-Ryback.
可恶的雷贝克
Shoot them down.
击落它们
I'd have to unlock Grazer from Washington.
我要解除瞄准华府
I don't have the transponder numbers. I can't target them!
没有异频雷达收发号码不能瞄准
They'd kill all the hostages.
他们会杀死所有人质
Turbulence.
颤动
If it moves, Grazer can see it.
若它移动  卫星可测到
They disturb the air as they fly through it.
他们飞过时会触动空气
Low-altitude turbulence, that's how you find these things.
低高度的颤动  便可以追测得到
There you are...
你在那儿
...Stealths.
隐形战机
I can target these.
我可瞄准它们
Lady!
小姐!
What's taking you so long?
你为何还不出来
You've had your two minutes.
两分钟已到了
We're the good guys.
我们是好人
Wait a minute. Where are you going?
慢着  你去哪里？
- They split up. - Is that a problem?
它们分开了
I won't get Grazer onto DC before it passes.
它飞过前我无法令卫星对准华府
Come out now.
快出来
I broke my bra.
我的胸罩断了
Tits to die for, huh?
难过美人关
Where are the hostages?
人质在哪儿？
They're upstairs! Go!
上层  去!
You first.
先击落你
Say good night, Gracie.
道别吧
Got you.
击落了
Ryback's hitting the hostage cars.
赖攻入人质车卡
Good old Ryback!
好一个雷贝克!
ATAC, Foxtrot Two. Target is locked on. I have tone.
狐步二号  已瞄准目标
Damn, I'm good.
我真行
Jesus.
天啊
Get me the President.
替我接总统
I'm coming to get my niece now.
我要去救我侄女了
Come and get her.
来救她吧
Why are you bringing Ryback here? Can you handle this?
你能应付吗？
It looks like you fucked up. It's time to cut and run.
看来你失败了  立即走吧
Excuse me?
什么？
Anyone else think I fucked up?
还有谁认为我失败？
The cars are separating!
列车分开了
What are you doing?
你做什么？
Coming to help you.
我来帮你
You're a hero now?
你现在是英雄了？
You're the hero.
你是英雄
We're free!
我们自由了!
You want to help? Climb up that ladder and commandeer that helo.
你想帮忙便爬上直升机指挥机师
Are you crazy? Climb up there?
你疯了吗？爬上去？
It might not work, but try.
可能会失败  但试试看
Where are you going?
你去哪儿？
The girl.
那女孩
Tranquility, this is Sparrow. I'm in position. Over.
宁静  这是麻雀
This is Tranquility. Hold position as planned. Out.
这是宁静  照计划保持原位
Hey, bring that ladder closer.
把梯子移近一点
Can't you see I'm trying to be a hero?
你看不见我想做英雄吗？
That's better.
这样才是
This is Sparrow. We made our first pickup.
这是麻雀  已接了第一个人
The hell you have. Get up there and deal with that.
你没有  快上去应付吧
What's going on?
什么回事？
Kick his butt!
揍他吧!
Honey, we sure taught that boy how to fly.
我们教他怎样飞
We sure did.
是的
Now we're going to keep this chopper right here.
现在把直升机停留在这儿
Or I'm going to blow your brains out! You got that, honey?
否则便杀了你  你明白吗？
Let me handle Ryback.
让我杀了雷贝克
You take care of the techno shit.
你应付技技方面的事
He's mine.
他是我的
I'll take him myself, hand to hand.
我亲手杀了他
Come on my little ghost satellites, I need you with me to hide my baby...
我的假卫星你们要掩掩我的宝贝
...so she can blow the fuck out of Washington.
好让它把华府炸个稀烂
Go get your throat ripped out.
你去送死吧
I got eight million people to kill, and one billion dollars to pick up.
我要杀八百万人和去拿十亿元
Thank you, sir.
谢谢
The President and staff have been evacuated.
总统等人已疏散了
Leaving millions of innocent people to die if we don't stop it.
若不能阻止会有百万计的人死亡
We must use Pegasus now.
现在要用科学卫星了
But, sir...
但是
...we still have eight possibilities.
仍有八个可能性
Pick one.
选一个吧
Now!
快!
Kappa.
K吧
Thank you. Kappa's the target. Stand by and launch.
谢谢  目标是K  准备发射
I've never been afraid of anybody.
我从不害怕任何人
But that uncle of yours scares me.
但你的叔叔使我害怕
And I like it.
我喜欢
It's you and me... or me and her.
你和我打  否则我和她同归于尽
Now, you hold on real tight and you'll stay in one piece.
你要抓紧否则粉身碎骨
Fuck, you ruined my coat.
你弄破我的外衣
Good morning.
早安
起来
Nobody beats me in the kitchen.
从没有人在厨房能胜过我
I must go. Won't need any of this anymore. Everything I need...
我走了  我不需要这些  我要的
...is right here.
在这儿
The Petrol Express will be here in a minute.
快车随时驶至
Have a nice life.
好好享受生命
What's left of it.
你的余生
You take one step and I'm dropping this grenade.
你再走近我便扔下手榴弹
Drop it.
扔吧
Pegasus missed.
没命中
It wasn't Kappa.
不是K
Jesus.
天啊
Shooting me won't do any good.
杀我不会有好处
ATAC can't get past my ghost satellites.
他们无法破我的假卫星
And you can't get past my encrypted program.
亦无法破我的密码程式
You mean to tell me there's no way I can shut that off?
你是说我无法把它关掉吗？
No way.
没办法
恢复控制游牧者一号
I never thought of that.
我倒没想过
It was Delta.
是D
We're locked on.
瞄准了
Hit it!
击中!
Hold the ladder. And keep this chopper right here.
稳定梯子  把直升机停在这儿
I never doubted you.
我从没怀疑你
Oh, yes, you did.
你有的
This is a real sweet Hallmark moment, but...
这是很动人的时刻
...can we go home now, Uncle Casey?
但我们可以回家去了吗  凯西叔
This is Helo 505 November-Mike.
这是505NM直升机
Sir, there's a message coming in. I'll patch it through.
有讯息  我转过来
This is Casey Ryback.
我是雷贝克
The hostages are safe.
人质安全